FOUR HANDS, TWO SONATAS
PRAGUE
We are at the Prague Harmonie
International Competition finals venue.
Today is the final round,
featuring the two finalists.
Following their exceptional
semifinal performances,
all attention is focused
on today's event.
Let go of me!
I said let go!
Where are we going now?
Excuse me.
Stop, stop!
I want to go to the toilet!
Are you listening to me?
I said I need to go to the restroom!
Cut the crap!
Or else I'll put a bullet
through your head.
Watch it!
No, you watch it.
Don't get blood splatter in the car.
Who do you think you are?
Don't tell me what to do.
FOUR HANDS, TWO SONATAS
We will now present
an award to Kang Pi-o…
6 MONTHS AGO
…for bringing honor
to Korea Arts High School.
Kang Pi-o, please come to the podium.
EPISODE 1
Is all this necessary?
You performed so much better.
"The above student
is hereby commended
for elevating our school's reputation
by winning the grand prize
at the 27th Lake Erie
International Junior Competition."
CERTIFICATE OF COMMENDATION
NAME: KANG PI-O
DROP OUT, BASTARD
LEAVE, ILLEGITIMATE CHILD
Han-rim, he's over here.
Hey, did you throw this in the trash?
You're so damn full of yourself.
The whole school gathered
for the stupid ceremony
because you won some competition.
You crossed the line, don't you think?
Hey.
Are we just here to make you look good?
Well, I suppose winning a competition
is nothing to Kang Seung-woon's grandson.
You think that's funny?
Let us in on the joke.
Do you think it's my fault
you guys didn't place?
If you're so bitter about not placing,
try to spend less time picking fights
and more time practicing.
Seriously?
What about you?
Aren't you trying to prove yourself
because you're bitter
about your family background?
-Hey!
-What the hell?
What are you guys doing?
-Jeez, it's her again.
-That scared me.
Why are you guys messing with Pi-o again?
Snap out of it, Hong Jae-in.
Stop letting this jerk use you.
Let's go.
Hey, wait up.
Wait, Pi-o!
How many times do I have to tell you?
Try to be just a little more humble.
Those guys are jealous of you as it is.
You didn't have to
throw away that certificate.
Or you could've thrown it away at home.
Why should I have to
cater to everyone else's feelings?
Are you…
a sociopath?
Why don't you tell me what you want?
Me?
I don't want anything.
Oh, yeah? Never mind then.
-Actually, I--
-Sorry.
Find someone else.
You didn't even hear me out.
Weren't you going to ask me
to be your accompanist?
How did you know?
Hey, Pi-o!
Just hear me out.
Pi-o.
I wouldn't ask you if I didn't have to.
But none of the others are any good.
There's no way I can play with them.
I'm busy.
It's not a lot. Just three…
No, wait.
Just twice.
Come on, it won't take up
much of your time.
Hey!
I'm practically begging you here!
I didn't want to say this,
but we're not on the same level.
Playing together
would only expose you.
Why play a concerto like that?
That's a pretty harsh thing to say.
But that's my point.
I'm asking you
to help me out with your skills.
No. I don't want to.
Hey, Kang Pi-o!
Hey, I'm talking to you!
Right.
This is exactly why
I can't lose you.
How do you capture Schumann so perfectly?
Pi-o.
Forget the accompaniment.
Let's just get married.
I seriously need to
listen to you play forever.
Will you just leave already?
Hey, I'm totally serious!
SONGMIN HIGH SCHOOL
Where are you going?
Get up, Choi Jeong-yo!
Everyone, gather around.
I want an answer now.
What will you do
about the music practical?
You really can't play a single instrument?
-Come on, a practical?
-We can't.
I told you a million times.
Bring a triangle or something
and take the practical.
Here's the alternative.
My friend called and said
they need to fill the seats.
If you attend,
I'll give you credit for the practical.
Is that better?
What a shame. I'll pass.
What do you mean?
I'm going out of my way
to cut you some slack.
No one goes to those things anymore.
This is way too much pressure.
Why don't you just give up on us?
-Choi Jeong-yo!
-Here!
I don't want to go.
Hello, Rider Jo!
That idiot.
Man, look at you being responsible
and coming to school every day.
Get into any trouble today?
Want me to get into serious trouble
and get expelled?
You're too chicken to do that.
-Hop on.
-All right, let's go.
Get your fast cash!
NEED CASH FAST?
A real man
never forgets the hard times
he went through.
You boys.
When you make it big someday,
remember me, okay?
Thank you, sir.
-Here.
-Thank you!
You punk.
I gave you a bit extra.
-Here. Work hard.
-Thank you.
-You can all be successful.
-Thank you, sir.
Hey, Jeong-yo.
Eat up, okay?
You've lost weight.
By the way, Jeong-yo,
tell your father to pay up what he owes.
I'm broke as hell right now.
Look at us,
just eating jjajangmyeon every day.
Hello, this is Happy Loan.
-How are you, ma'am?
-Forget it.
-I mean, miss.
-Take it, you punk.
Don't be so stubborn.
Hurry up and eat.
MUSICAL INSTRUMENT ARCADE
TRADITIONAL MARKET
I told you to stop bringing me money,
damn it!
It makes it impossible
for me to hate you in peace.
Hey.
Do you feel sorry for me?
Is that why you keep bringing me money?
You're pitiful too.
And so am I.
You're pitiful…
and I'm pitiful too.
GRAND PRIZE
PIANO, CHOI JEONG-YO
NOTICE OF OVERDUE HEALTH INSURANCE PREMIUM
NOTICE OF OVERDUE INTEREST
-Hello.
-Hey.
-Taking good care of yourself?
-Yes, ma'am.
It feels amazing
to finally watch a proper performance.
How is Hyun-soo still so good
after all this time?
Most people lose their touch
and just go through the motions
when they hit middle age.
Maestro Kang made it so obvious
he was fond of Hyun-soo.
He won't even shake hands
if he doesn't like a performance.
A conductor shouldn't be
so transparent with his emotions.
It intimidates the people he works with.
Yes, I suppose you're right.
Did you find an orchestra
for the concerto?
Oh, I have meetings next week
with the Gyeongseong Philharmonic
and the Seonghan Philharmonic.
Don't worry about a thing.
It's Pi-o. Who would turn him down?
I know you're busy
trying to win Hyun-soo over,
but if you neglect my son because of it,
I'll terminate our contract.
Come on. I wouldn't do that.
The entire company is focused on him.
By the way, Jae-in said
you refused to be her accompanist.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
You made the right call.
Honestly, it'd benefit me more
if you spent that time practicing
than helping that brat out.
And I don't want your mom
to come after me.
I'd love to stay here.
Performing with you today made me realize
what a privilege it is to play with you.
Not at all, sir. You're too kind.
You're home.
Hey, you're here.
Mr. Kang felt it was too early
to call it a night, so…
I enjoyed your performance today.
Thanks.
I heard Hyun-jeong's company
made you an offer.
Yes, I've decided to stay
in Korea for a while.
You've probably had dinner already,
so join us for a drink.
No, thank you.
You must be Pi-o.
I've heard a lot about you.
You took first place at Lake Erie?
As expected of your grandson, sir.
He must've inherited your musical talent.
Stop talking nonsense.
Don't give a talentless kid false hope,
and be careful with your praise.
Empty praise does more harm than good.
-Father.
-Go upstairs.
I don't want to ruin my night.
How could you say that
in front of Hyun-soo?
You can hate me all you want!
But why say things like that
with Pi-o right there?
Don't expect me to live through your child
the way you do.
But he's still your grandson,
and he's my son!
Don't fool yourself.
The only reason I let you two live here
is out of pity for you
trying to play mother,
not because I accept him as my grandson.
Why can't you accept him? Why?
You expect me to accept a kid
with no known father as my grandson?
But more than that,
he doesn't have what it takes.
Stop wasting your time
on that hopeless fool
and focus on your own life!
Father!
Start playing.
Hail, Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is
the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners,
now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
Come in.
I have something to tell you.
Do you really think
I don't have what it takes?
Or do you just want to think that
because you hate me?
I've looked up to you since I was little.
I gave it everything I had
just to earn one compliment from you.
But even after I took first place
in so many competitions,
you never once glanced at me.
If it's because you hate me--
So you're asking…
why I'd put down a talented kid like you
just because of my personal feelings.
Is that it?
What do you think you're doing?
You think I care to see you
show off your technique?
You have the nerve to complain
about fairness with skills like this?
With a performance
full of nothing but hollow desire?
The people I despise the most in the world
are those who mistake
the greatness of their music
for proof that they themselves are great.
Unfortunately,
you're one of them.
I've never thought of myself that way!
All I wanted was your approval.
Is that so wrong?
Just once.
Give me one more chance.
If you still say no
after I play for you again,
I'll quit playing the piano.
I don't have time to spare for you.
Even for the Noblesse Classical Concert?
You arrogant fool.
Winning a few competitions
has made you laughably arrogant.
What if I do get to play there?
Will you come watch me perform?
Fine.
Let's see you try.
But if I still feel the same way then…
you'll need to take responsibility
for what you said.
That's absurd.
You can't change teachers
right before the competition.
You know how important it is
to get into Professor Seo's inner circle.
That's not important to me.
I need a real teacher
who can teach me properly.
How could that…
How could that not be important?
It all comes down to business in the end.
And of all people,
why does it have to be Hyun-soo?
He has exceptional talent,
but he's still only a performer.
I told Grandfather
that he'd see me perform
at the Noblesse Classical Concert.
And I told him I'd quit the piano
if he still didn't approve.
Do you really think Professor Seo
could pull that off?
Why did you say that
without talking to me…
Pi-o!
Are you off to school?
Have a good day.
I have to say, Pi-o is smart.
He knows exactly what he needs.
You talk like
it doesn't concern you at all.
Why are you being so hostile?
Let's be honest.
Everyone in the music industry knows
Professor Seo is overrated.
I think Pi-o made the right call.
If only Father had supported him,
he wouldn't have had to
turn to Professor Seo.
How could you possibly know what it's like
to be completely powerless, Mother?
You're really good.
I can't find a single flaw.
Why did you come to me?
You don't need my help.
That's not true.
You didn't like how I played.
That isn't true.
You should just learn from Professor Seo.
What did he say?
You have the nerve to complain
about fairness with skills like this?
With a performance
full of nothing but hollow desire?
ARTS & MUSIC HALL
Man, I'm dying here.
I can't listen to this anymore.
-Let's go.
-All right.
-Hurry up before the teacher sees us.
-Okay.
Let's go.
Come on, Jeong-yo. Let's go.
You guys go ahead.
KANG PI-O (17 YEARS OLD)
KOREA ARTS HIGH SCHOOL
Kang Pi-o?
Hey, do you have an extra handkerchief?
What's your name?
Kang Pi-o.
KANG PI-O
1ST PRIZE
Look over here, please!
-Pi-o!
-Over here!
Can we get a photo?
They know how amazing you are, don't they?
-Look over here!
-Please, Pi-o!
Why are you so upset?
Kang Pi-o, the perfectionist.
What didn't you like?
My cadenza was a disaster.
CADENZA: A VIRTUOSIC, IMPROVISED SOLO
NEAR THE END OF A CONCERTO MOVEMENT
It wasn't like that during practice.
You know, I've been thinking.
Overdoing it in the cadenza
is a bit tacky.
Playing it with a lighter touch
actually blended better
with the orchestra today.
A pianist shouldn't
race ahead of the music, right?
-Hey, Pi-o!
-Pi-o!
-Hello, ma'am.
-Get in, kids.
I left my sheet music in the waiting room.
Go get it.
Wait for me.
5TH CHEONGUN
INTERNATIONAL MUSIC COMPETITION
Are you sure you can cut class like this?
Your teacher won't say anything?
My future husband's
military exemption is on the line.
You think class matters?
Cut it out.
Who's that?
Who's playing so well?
Damn it.
Hey, Pi-o.
Find out who that is.
Hello, teacher.
I caught a cold.
KANG PI-O
Who are you?
Who the hell are you,
looking at my sheet music like that?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to.
Hey.
Don't you remember me?
Who are you?
Never mind. I'm sorry.
By the way,
your cadenza sounded a bit dry.
Was that intentional?
I just…
That's just what I thought.
Critique me however you want.
But if you're such an expert,
why don't you get up on stage
instead of running your mouth?
Was that you playing just now?
That's amazing.
Hey, you were really good.
What school do you go to?
Seonye? Deokmyeong?
Hey, hold on.
Wait a minute!
"Songmin"?
That's not an arts high school.
This is even more amazing.
Hey, can I get your number?
-You see, I play the viola--
-Leave me alone.
Hey!
By the way,
your cadenza sounded a bit dry.
Was that intentional?
KANG PI-O
1ST PRIZE
MUSICAL INSTRUMENT STREET
Hey, why aren't you playing?
Ma'am, the thing is…
The way you play is a bit emotionless.
Can you put some life into it?
The notes sound flat and lifeless to me.
What are you saying?
Focus on your own playing.
I know I'm not good.
That's why if you don't play well,
we're both doomed.
If you're so dissatisfied,
find another accompanist.
Wait, ma'am. That's not what I meant.
Ma'am?
Ma'am!
SONGMIN HIGH SCHOOL
She's pretty.
Jeez!
-Lucky you, man.
-Leave.
Who are you?
Oh my.
You don't remember me?
We met at the music hall.
What is she talking about?
I was totally blown away
when I heard you play.
And I'm looking for an accompanist.
So can you please do it?
Get lost.
Seriously? You didn't even hear the offer.
I'll pay you really well
for the accompaniment.
I said get lost.
Okay, then how about this?
My mom
is the head of a classical music agency.
I'll talk to her and get you an audition.
The way I see it, you're a genius.
Are you going to let your genius
go to waste like this?
Genius, my foot. Go be a genius yourself.
I don't need that nonsense.
A million won!
Don't tell me
you thought I'd pay you peanuts?
Of course not.
Normally, I pay 100,000 won per session.
But since you're special,
I'll pay you 200,000 won.
So five sessions would earn you…
a million won.
Sounds like a really good gig, right?
You arrogant punk!
So tell me.
What's wrong with my teaching?
What's the problem?
I'm running an entrance exam business
and don't care about music, is that it?
Tell me the truth. Who is it?
You want to switch to another professor,
but you feel bad leaving,
so you're trying to blame me, right?
It's not like that, sir.
Oh, come on. "It's not like that"?
Like hell it isn't.
I don't think it's right,
but you keep telling me
to follow your playing technique!
I'll just end up a carbon copy of you!
What?
Damn it.
Get out.
I never want to see you again.
I'm going to do everything in my power
to get you blacklisted
in the music industry.
Now get out.
Get out!
Hey, Choi Jeong-yo!
Let's go.
You practiced, right?
Let's hear you play.
Pay me first.
You're something else.
Here.
I'll give you the rest afterward.
That's okay, right?
Go ahead then.
-Get home safely.
-Okay.
And give some serious thought
to serving on the gifted school
audition panel, all right?
I'll do that.
I wonder who we'll get this year.
We had many violinists last year…
What is it?
Who are you?
What school do you attend?
He's from another school.
I just brought him as my accompanist.
Is that so?
Wait.
Hey, stop right there!
Wait a minute!
Let go of me!
I just came here for the gig!
I want my money first. It's 100,000 won.
Here you go.
Play the piece from earlier.
Can you try modulating?
Okay. Can you try a variation next?
What's your name?
Choi Jeong-yo.
Jeong-yo.
Where are you taking piano lessons?
-I'm not taking any.
-What?
I just play the piano at home
when I'm bored.
Why don't you
enroll here and get some proper training?
So that's why you wanted to see me.
I'm sorry, but I'm not that stupid.
What do you mean?
You're trying to recruit students
and shake them down.
I don't have any money.
Goodbye.
That's not true.
If you want,
we can provide everything,
including a dorm room.
Our school has a scholarship program
for gifted students.
Forget about tuition or lesson fees.
You'd just have to focus on
playing the piano.
And after that?
How would I make a living as a pianist?
I mean, people like you
have a lot of money,
so you can afford to be artists, but me?
Man…
I'll starve to death as a pianist.
Have a nice day.
Wait a minute.
Call me if you ever change your mind.
As far as I can tell,
you've got nothing to worry about.
Reach out to me whenever.
Okay?
Sure.
Goodbye.
What just happened?
Did the director
just offer you a scholarship?
That's crazy!
See?
I told you that you're a genius.
I knew it. My intuition is never wrong.
So? You're going to transfer here, right?
No.
What? Are you insane?
Trust me,
people are desperate
to get into this school.
Pull yourself together
and think this through.
This is a rare opportunity.
I don't want to.
Seriously?
Why not? Give me a reason.
I don't know. I just don't want to.
Why are you making a fuss?
Are you in on this too?
Who on earth is that kid?
It's not refined yet,
but his raw talent is exceptional.
I haven't heard anyone
play like that before.
But still,
what made you suggest
he transfer right away?
It was about seven years ago.
I went to judge a competition,
and I saw this kid.
For some reason,
I just couldn't forget his performance.
I've regretted letting him go ever since.
And that kid's name was
Choi Jeong-yo.
Dude, help me choose between these.
NEED CASH FAST?
KOREA ARTS HIGH SCHOOL
DIRECTOR YOON SEON-JU
Why don't you enroll here
and get some proper training?
Is that you, Dad?
Hey, search the place.
Is he here?
No, sir.
Damn it.
Kid, where did your dad run off to?
I don't know.
"I don't know"?
Damn it.
Come here.
Hold still. I'll be gentle.
Here it is.
Good. This should still work.
Call your dad, kid.
Tell him to come right now.
Here.
That's it.
Jeez.
Give me a cigarette.
Kim is on his way to get you.
Run away now!
Hey, what's taking so long--
Get him!
-Shit.
-Stop right there!
Damn, I'm exhausted.
-We got you now…
-Get him.
Don't lose him.
-Go after him.
-You're so dead.
What are you doing here?
Drink this and dry off before you leave.
You'll catch a cold.
Please.
Be honest with me
and tell me what my problem is.
I'm losing my mind over this.
Everyone just says I'm playing well.
But I know that's not true.
I can't tell if they're clueless
or just pretending to be.
But you know the truth.
Right?
You're right.
I think there's a problem with your music.
Ultimately, your performance
doesn't sound like your own.
Right now, your superb technique
is masking your flaws.
But if you listen closely,
you'll realize that your music is fake.
I admit your technique is flawless.
But music isn't just about technique.
You have to own the emotions
behind that sheet music.
Your pain, your joy, your despair.
Unless you move the audience
with those emotions…
you'll never be a true musician.
Do you have a room available?
We don't accept minors.
Why not?
Come on, I have money.
Just give me a room.
Leave.
DIRECTOR YOON SEON-JU
Hello?
This is Choi Jeong-yo.
Can I stay in the dorm…
for a few days?
Given your situation,
why don't you just transfer to our school?
This isn't pity or charity,
so don't overthink it.
Recruiting smart and talented students
is a huge achievement for me.
And you're a very good candidate.
The phone is turned off.
You will be connected to voicemail
after the beep…
DAD
11:30 P.M.
CHOI JEONG-YO
Attention, everyone.
We have a new transfer student.
Make sure to help him out.
Go ahead and introduce yourself.
Hi, everyone.
Hello.
I see a new face.
-He's a transfer.
-He just transferred.
What's your name?
It's Choi Jeong-yo.
What do you play?
The piano.
Hey, just like you.
Really?
Come to the front.
Play something.
What are you waiting for? Just play.
I…
Can I do it another time?
-What's with him?
-How impressive.
Jeez.
Okay then.
I'm sorry.
All right then.
Let's start at page 139 today.
"Choi Jeong-yo."
How much?
How much did you donate to get in?
Piano, right?
How many? Two or three?
Why won't you tell us?
Hey.
Keep this up, and you're dead.
Gosh, I'm so scared.
Man, you've got no class at all.
It's transfers like him
who drag our school's name
through the mud.
This one brings zero substance
or qualifications.
Move.
What?
I need to get my book, so move.
Make me.
Hey, hey!
What are you boys doing?
You little punks.
Get back in your seats.
Thanks for earlier.
For what?
You stopped them for me.
I didn't stop them.
I was just getting my book.
That's where we sign up
to reserve a practice room?
Where's the snack bar?
You don't live in the dorms, do you?
Why is everything so complicated here?
There are so many classes,
and they're weird.
That's enough.
What is?
I'm not into making friends.
You're on your own.
PRACTICE ROOM RESERVATIONS
Hey, do you have an extra handkerchief?
The grand prize goes to
Choi Jeong-yo!
Have you lost your mind?
How could you place second?
FOUR HANDS, TWO SONATAS
You really don't remember me?
There's something I haven't told you.
Just go study abroad.
You think I'd run off
to study abroad like a coward?
How about playing four hands?
I'm sure you know Choi Jeong-yo.
You're using copies
because you can't afford sheet music?
Don't do it!
Why him, of all people?
Have you listened to him play?
I hate bastards like you
who play music with that attitude.
I'm afraid
Choi Jeong-yo will be held accountable.
I'll have him expelled.
Subtitle translation by: Jenny Kim